Guide to the Fritz Leiber Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Fritz Leiber Papers
1930-1996
03/1984-003
Leiber, Fritz, 1910-1992
30.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The Fritz Leiber Papers contains correspondence, notes, manuscripts, typescripts, publications and tearsheets, diaries and biographical materials, financial, legal and medical records, photographs, illustrations, convention materials, and miscellaneous materials. Additional oversize art/illustration materials and ephemera such as weaponry, sculpture, and awards are housed separately. The materials date from the 1930s to the 1980s. They are housed in 60 manuscripts boxes, 5 storage boxes, and 3 oversized boxes.
Biographical Information:
Fritz Reuter Leiber, Jr. was born in Chicago on December 24, 1910 to Shakespearean actors Fritz Leiber, Sr. and Virginia Bronson Leiber. He graduated from the University of Chicago in 1932 with a degree in psychology and physiology, and, in 1936, married Jonquil Stephens, a British poet with similar interests in the supernatural. They had one son, Justin Leiber, in 1938. Several years after Jonquil's death in 1969, he married Margo Skinner. His employment throughout the years included editorial positions and teaching drama, but Fritz Leiber primarily supported himself with his writing.
Producing stories in the genres of fantasy, science, horror, and supernatural fiction from the mid 1930s until his death in 1992, Fritz Leiber won several prominent fantasy and science fiction awards such as the Hugo, the Nebula, and the World Fantasy Association Awards. Although he wrote numerous stories in variety of styles, Leiber is perhaps best known for the heroic Fafhrd and the Gray Mouser characters he created with his college friend, Harry Otto Fischer (1910-1986), and which he continued to embellish through a series of short stories and novels throughout his long writing career and correspondence with Fischer.
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre); Photographs; Records (documents)
Personal Name:
Leiber, Fritz, 1910-1992
Topical Term:
Authors -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century; Fantasy fiction, American; Horror tales, American; Science fiction, American
Acquisition Information:
The collection was donated to the University of Houston by Fritz Leiber and Justin Leiber, his son, between 1984 and 1997. Additional correspondence between Fritz Leiber and Franklin C. MacKnight was donated by Dr. MacKnight.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Related Materials:
Fritz Leiber Science Fiction & Fantasy Convention Flyers & Programs digital collection
http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/1984_003
Scope and Contents
The Fritz Leiber Papers contains correspondence, notes, manuscripts, typescripts, publications and tearsheets, diaries and biographical materials, financial, legal and medical records, photographs, illustrations, convention materials, and miscellaneous materials. Additional oversize art/illustration materials and ephemera such as weaponry, sculpture, and awards are housed separately. The materials date from the 1930s to the 1980s. They are housed in 60 manuscripts boxes, 5 storage boxes, and 3 oversized boxes.
The collection was compiled from 41 boxes of previously unprocessed Fritz Leiber materials, 23 boxes of Fritz Leiber papers which were processed in 1991-1992, and several boxes of letters which were donated by Franklin C. MacKnight from 1984-1991. Original provenance was lost through preliminary processing, so the order imposed on the Fritz Leiber Papers is artificial and reflects the major categories discovered during final processing. For more information, please refer to the series descriptions.
Detailed List of Contents
- Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes correspondence between Fritz Leiber and friends, editors, and fans with the largest series being between Fritz Leiber and his friends Harry Otto Fischer and F.C. MacKnight. Correspondence is filed alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, then by written or inferred date. Partially dated or undated materials are filed behind all dated materials.
  - Assorted letters to Leiber (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A-Als (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Altshuler, Harry (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - An-Ao (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ap-Az (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B-Bak (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ballantine Books (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ballentine, Betty-Ballentine, Ian (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Balm-Bb (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Beach, Margaret, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beach, Margaret, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Beach, Margaret, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beach, Margaret, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beb-Bird (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Blanchette, Cindy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bloch, Robert, 1957-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bloch, Robert, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Blp-Broo (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brower, Jeff (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Browf-Bz (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - C-Cart (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ce-Cn (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Co-Cole (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Com-Cz (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - D-DeA (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - de Camp, Catherine-de Camp, L. Sprague (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - de G-Dew (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dexter, Susan, January-June 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dexter, Susan, July-December 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dexter, Susan, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dexter, Susan (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Df-Dz (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - E-Eng (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Enzenbacher, Dale (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Enz-Eu (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Evans, Lynn Anne, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Evans, Lynn Anne, January-June 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Evans, Lynn Anne, July-December 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Evans, Lynn Anne, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Evb (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fantasy Newsletter (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fantasy Tales-Fischer, Giles (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fischer, Harry to Atheneum Publishers, November 3, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1963-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fischer, Harry, January-June 1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fischer, Harry, July-December 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fischer, Harry (to Leiber, Justin)-Fischer, Sharon (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fj-Fz (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - G-Gar (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gas-Gx (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gygax, Gary-Gygax, Mary (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - H-Hh (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Hi-Ht (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Hu-Hz (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - I (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - J (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - K-Kem (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ken-Kra (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Krb-Kz (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - L-Lang (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Laur-Leiber, Frank (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Leiber, Fritz - General Letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Leiber, Fritz - First Names Only (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Leiber, Fritz to A-B (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Leiber, Fritz to C (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Leiber, Fritz to D (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Leiber, Fritz to E-Fischer, Giles (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Fischer, Harry, 1957-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Fj-G (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Leiber, Fritz to H-K (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Jonquil Stephens (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1946-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin, 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Leiber, Justin (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Lej-Lz (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Leiber, Fritz to MacKnight, F.C., 1934?-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Leiber, Fritz to MacKnight, F.C., 1951-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Leiber, Fritz to MacKnight, F.C., 1974-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Leiber, Fritz to MacKnight, F.C., 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Leiber, Fritz to MacKnight, F.C., 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Mc (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Leiber, Fritz to M-Meg (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Merril, Judy (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Mills, Robert (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Missiles from the Mailbox (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Mo-Nu (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Leiber, Fritz to P-Po (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Leiber, Fritz to Pp-R (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Leiber, Fritz to S-T (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Leiber, Fritz to U-Wg (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Leiber, Fritz to White, Flora (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Leiber, Fritz to White, Ted-Z (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Leiber, Jonquil (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1967-1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, 1986-1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Leiber, Justin to Leiber, Fritz, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Leiber, Justin to White, Flora, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Leiber, Justin to White, Flora, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lej-Lit (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Lockwood, Myna (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Locus-Lz (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1964-1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - MacKnight, F.C., 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - MacKnight, F.C. to Leiber, Justin (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - MacKnight, F.C. to Skinner, Margo (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Mc (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - M-Marb (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Marron, Lynn, 1969-1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mars-Meg (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Merril, Judith, 1961-1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Merril, Judith, 1971-1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mes-Mez (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mi-Mills, Richard (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Mills, Robert, 1964-1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Mills, Robert, 1978-1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Min-Mom (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Mon-Moo (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mop-Moss, N (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mun-Mz (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - N-Nue (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1976 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1984 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Nurss, Dolores J., undated (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
  - O-Pak (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Palmer, Doug, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Palmer, E.-Pas (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Patrick, Arlynn, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Patrick, Arlynn, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Pb-Po (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pocsik, John, 1964-1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pocsik, John, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Pod-Preiss (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Presser, Arlynn Leiber (Patrick), 1988-1991 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Prf-Pz (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Q (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - R-Re (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Rh-Ri (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ro-Rose (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Rothbell-Sheckley, Jay (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Rox-Rup (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Russ, Joanna (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Russell-Rz (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - S-Sche (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1969-1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, January-September 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, October-December 1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Schiff, Stuart David, 1982-1992 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sci (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Schm-Scz (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Se-Sh (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Sidney-Fryer, Don, 1973-1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Sidney-Fryer, Don, 1979-1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sie (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Skinner, Margo (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Sl-Slate (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Slattery, Tom, 1970-1978 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Slattery, Tom, 1979-1981 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Slattery, Tom, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Slattery, Tom, 1984-1990 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Slattery, Tom, 1974-1989 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Sm-Sto (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Strang, Leslie, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Strang, Leslie, 1978-1983 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Str-Sz (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - T-Tr (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Ts-Tz (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - U (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - V (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Wade, James, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Wade, James, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Wade, James, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Wade, James, 1980-1983 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Wae-Weh (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Wei-Whit (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - The White House (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - White, Flora, 1973-1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - White, Flora, 1976-1979 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - White, Flora, 1978-1980 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - White, Flora, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - White, Flora, 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - White, Flora, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - White, T-Woodward, B. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Woodward, Sheila, 1968-1980 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Woodward, Sheila, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - World-Wz (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - X-Z (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Unknown recipients, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Notes
  This series contains handwritten or typed notes for various Fritz Leiber stories. Notes are filed alphabetically by the title of the work. Unidentifiable notes are filed last.
  - 6 Miles Nearer Heaven (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The Abyssal Bubble (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Alice and the Allergy (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - All the Weed in the World (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - America the Beautiful (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Animus (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Auto-da-furia (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The Automatic Pistol (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - A Bad Day for Sales (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - The Bait (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - The Beat Cluster (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Belsen Express (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Belsen Express - Introduction (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - The Big Engine (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - The Big Holiday (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - The Big Time (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - The Big Trek (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - A Bit of the Dark World (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - The Black Corridor (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - The Black Ewe (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - The Black Gondolier (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Black has its Charms (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - The Book of Fritz Leiber (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Bread Overhead (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Bullet with his Name (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - The Bump (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - A Case of Identity (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - The Casket Demon (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Cat Three (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Catch that Zeppelin (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Cats' Cradle (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - The Change War Series[?] (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Coming Attraction (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Conjure Wife (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Crazy Annaoj (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - The Creature from Cleveland's Depths (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Crimes against Passion (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Cry Witch! (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - The Crystal Prison (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Cyclops (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Damnation Morning (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Dark Wings (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Day Dark, Night Bright (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Deadly Moon (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - The Death of Princes (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - A Defense of Werewolves (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - A Deskful of Girls (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Diary in the Snow (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Do You Know Dave Wenzel? (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Dr. Adams' Garden of Evil (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Dr. Krometusky's Day (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - The Eeriest Ruined Dawn World (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - The Enchanted Forest (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - Endfray of the Ofay (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Endfray of the Ofay - Introduction (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - An Essay on Behaviorism (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Essay on the Greatness in Man and in Nature (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Ethics Pertaining to the Uses… (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Fafhrd and Me (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - Fafhrd and the Gray Mouser (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - [Fafhrd and the Gray Mouser] (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Fantasy Novel Equivalent (Box 21, Folder 62)
  - Four Ghosts in Hamlet (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Friends and Enemies (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Fritz Leiber Readings (Box 21, Folder 65)
  - Game for a Motel Room (Box 21, Folder 66)
  - The Game of Lankhmar (Box 21, Folder 67)
  - Grandmaster (Box 21, Folder 68)
  - Gray Warlock (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - [H.P. Lovecraft] (Box 21, Folder 70)
  - The Haunted Chessboard (Box 21, Folder 71)
  - The Horror from the Hurricane or, High Tide of Terror (Box 21, Folder 72)
  - How to Live with Machines (Box 21, Folder 73)
  - The Hurricane Horror (Box 21, Folder 74)
  - In Praise of Horror (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ingredients of My Writing (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Lovecraft: An Literary Copernicus (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Man who Loved Insane Girls (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Masculinity and Femininity (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Memoirs of a Fantasy Man (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Mighty Tides (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Moods: A Study (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - The Moon Porthole (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes for Star Guide (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - My Japanese Clock (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Mysterious Doings in the Metropolitan Museum (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Myths My Great-Granddaughter Taught Me (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - New Purposes (Box 22, Folder 14-15)
  - Night Monsters (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Night of the Wolf[?] (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Observations (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Operation Redemption (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Our Lady of Darkness (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Philosopher's Stone (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Poor Superman (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Reminiscences (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Richmond (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Rime Isle (Box 22, Folder 25-26)
  - San Francisco's Resident Detection (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Science Fiction: The Writers Speak (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Sea Magic (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - The Second Book of Fritz Leiber (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - The Shadow of a Cyclist (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Ship of Shadows (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Space and Time Structure (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Space Shack (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - A Specter is Haunting Texas (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Swords and Destinies (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Tales of the Grain Ships (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - The Terror from the Depths (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Through Hyperspace with Brown Jenkin (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Time and the Nth Dimension (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Trapped in the Sea of Stars (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Under the Thumbs of the Gods (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Waif (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - The Wanderer (Box 22, Folder 44-45)
  - Wars of the Wolves (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - The Wierdness [sic] from the Waves (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - The Winter Flies (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - The World of Fritz Leiber (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - X-mas Letter (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - You're All Alone (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - You're Dreaming Now (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - Untitled, unknown, and miscelleneous notes (Box 23, Folder 1-34)
- Writings
  Fritz Leiber's manuscripts and typescripts filed alphabetically by title. Works include but are not limited to short stories, novels, fantasy magazine columns, scientific articles, astronomical/astrological, and poetry.
  - Writings (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
  - Writings p. 3-57 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Writings p. 68-133 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Writings p. 136 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Writings (Box 24, Folder 8-15)
  - Author's Introduction (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Introduction - Galleys (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Introduction (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - [Bergman, Ingmar] (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - [Broussard, Francois] (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - [Ellison, Harlan] (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - [Fundamentals/Living Alone] (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - [Game of Lankhmar] (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - [Lovecraft, H.P.] (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - [Motion Pictures/Television Proposals/Adaptations] (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - [Wade, James] (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - 1979: Retrospect and Prospect (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Ad Astra per Asparagus (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - All for Art (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - All the Stage's a World (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Aloft 1202 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Anecdotes and Science (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Answering Service (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - Archeologists Handbook (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Author's introduction (see also: Publications - The Churchman) (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Auto-da-furia (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - The Automatic Pistol (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - The Bait (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Be of Good Cheer (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - The Beat Cluster (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Beauty and the Bast (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - The Bee Who Didn't Know What to Do (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Belsen Express - Introduction (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Best Friend (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Best of Fritz Leiber (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Big Engine (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - The Big Time (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - The Big Time - Introduction (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - The Big Time - Dramatization (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - The Big Trek (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - Birthpangs of Hybonia - Introduction (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - The Black Adept - Screenplay and Shooting Script (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - The Black Adept - Author's copy (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - The Black Goggles of Dr. Dragonet (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - Black has its Charms (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Blackballed! (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Blood Ritual - Chapter 1 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Blood Ritual - Chapter 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Blood Ritual - Chapter 3 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Blood Ritual - Chapter 4 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Book of Fritz Leiber - Afterword (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Buck Rogers, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 7a)
    Note: The comic strip artwork to accompany this typescript can be found in Box 67.
  - The Bump (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - The Button Molder (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - The Cat Hotel (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Cat Three (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Catch that Zeppelin (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Cats' Cradle (Box 25, Folder 13-14)
  - The Change War Series (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - The Changing Face of Horror (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
  - The Charm of 007 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - The Christmas Syndrome (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Clear Speech (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Come to the Fair (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Crazy Annaoj (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Crimes against Passion (Box 25, Folder 23-24)
  - The Crystal Prison (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Cyclops (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Dark Wings (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Day Dark, Night Bright (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Deadly Moon (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - The Dealings of Daniel Kesserich (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - Death Gets Busy, or, The Sadness of the Executioner (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - A Defense of Fantasy (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Depression Sale (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Destiny Times Three - Author's introduction (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - The Devil of It (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Difficulties in Idealism (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Do You Know Dave Wenzel? (Box 26, Folder 12)